In this video, we'll introduce how sponsored display can help drive traffic to your detail pages
and how you can set up your own sponsored display campaigns in the Advertising Console.
Sponsored display allows you to create display ads that can appear when shoppers browse, research,
or buy products in the Amazon store.
Sponsored display ads can appear on the Amazon homepage, product detail pages, shopping results,
Twitch, as well as other sites where shoppers spend time.
These ads can link shoppers directly to your product detail pages to learn more about your brand.
Sponsored display ads are automatically generated from product detail pages and include product
features like price and star rating alongside images.
This allows you to quickly set up display ads to reach shoppers in new placements.
Now let's learn how to get started with your first sponsored display campaign.
First, define your campaign goals.
Before you start, consider the goals of your campaign.
Sponsored display can help you achieve a variety of advertising goals, like awareness, consideration,
and purchase.
Depending on your goal, you may want to evaluate different metrics to assess your campaign's performance.
Second, create a campaign.
Now that you've identified your goals, sign into your Advertising Console account and click Create
Campaign.
Then choose Sponsored Display and click Continue.
Third, choose your campaign settings.
Choose a campaign name that is easy to identify and remember.
Note that this campaign name is only visible to you.
Next, enter the start and end dates for your campaign.
Remember, it's recommended to create your campaign with no end date so it can run year-round unless
you have a specific seasonal goal.
Finally, set your daily budget.
Fourth, create an ad group and choose your ad group settings.
Ad groups are groups of ads within a campaign that share the same creative type or set of targeting
tactics.
The first ad group is created when you create a campaign.
You can add more ad groups to the campaign after you've saved it.
Give your ad group a name that is descriptive and meaningful to you based on the products that you
want to advertise.
Fifth, customize your bidding strategies.
Choose a bidding strategy that lets Amazon optimize your bids against specific metrics.
You can choose to optimize for reach, page visits, or conversions.
Bids automatically adjust based on relevance while still allowing you to change your bid or pause
your campaign.
Sixth, select an ad format.
Ad formats can help you create an ad based on what you want to promote.
Sponsored display gives you access to two ad formats, image and video.
The image ad format lets you promote unique collections of products or existing stores, while the
video format lets you feature a single product.
The image creative for your campaign is automatically generated from the product detail page.
You can customize the default image creative with your brand logo, headline, and lifestyle imagery.
To create a sponsored display campaign with video, you'll need to upload an existing video asset
that features a single product or brand.
Seventh, choose your products.
We recommend adding 10 or more retail ready products to ensure your audiences see products that
are ready to be advertised.
Eighth, choose your targeting tactic.
Sponsored display gives you the option to choose between contextual targeting and audiences.
Note that only one targeting type per campaign is supported.
Contextual targeting lets you choose specific products or categories to target your ads.
You can show ads to shoppers who are currently visiting products and categories that you select
and similar products.
With different selected targets, you can choose to reach new audiences across diverse contexts on
their shopping and entertainment on Amazon and wherever they spend time, as well as on Amazon product
detail pages.
Audiences let you choose which audiences you want to see your ads.
You can reach relevant audiences through their shopping and entertainment journey inside and outside
the Amazon store using shopping and streaming signals from Amazon.
You have the option to combine multiple audiences in a single campaign, which can create a broader
audience for your ads while removing the risk of overlap.
Ninth, provide your targeting details.
Pending your targeting tactic selection, your final step will be to provide different targeting
details.
If you choose contextual targeting as your targeting tactic, here you can select categories, products,
brands, or features related to your product.
If you choose audiences as your targeting tactic, here you can further refine audiences by brand,
price range, star rating, and shipping eligibility.
Once you complete these steps, you're ready to launch your first sponsored display campaign.
Ready to get started?
Visit ads.
amazon.
com.